

# JERED DANIELSON

# HYBRID UX/DEV POWERHOUSE

## CONTACT

C

612-220-1735



jered@uw.edu



Seattle, WA 98168



/in/jereddanielson



https://jered.io



jereddanielson

#### CHRONOLOGY

#### Indeed, Inc.

The #1 job site in the world with 250+ million unique users/month

Lead UX Developer Jan 2022 – Present

Senior UX Developer Feb 2019 – December 2022

Design Technologist Jan 2018 – Jan 2019

## нво

UX Prototype Developer *Dec 2016*– *Dec 2017* 

## **Tectonic Design Studio**

UX Designer & Prototyping *June* 2014 – Nov 2016

## EDUCATION

## **University of Washington**

Bach. Des. in Interaction Design Aug 2012 – June 2015

#### OTHER

Ada Developers Academy Mentor & Tutor Since 2022

# **EXECUTIVE SUMMARY -**

User Interface expert with 8 years' experience in UX, front-end development, internal tools and prototyping. Combines deep knowledge of user needs with technical ingenuity to build world-class applications. Avid mentor, manager, team leader, and force multiplier. Comfortable working at large scale to serve 13+ million users. Tireless self-motivated learner. Passionate about emerging technologies and actively pushing the technological envelope.

# EXPERIENCE -

# Lead UX Developer

Indeed, Inc. | 3 roles | 2018 - Present

Joined the Job Seeker Profile team to elevate the user experience via high fidelity prototypes and experimental UI. Promoted to Lead UX Developer while growing the Design Engineering cohort from 2 to 6 developers and accumulating 4 direct reports as a manager. Spearheaded the launch of a revamped webapp from scratch which has grown to serve 3 million daily users. Trusted cross-functional subject matter expert.

- ▶ Proactively developed an internal tool to label data as input for machine learning models. As a result we both improved the accuracy of data parsing by 10% and reduced reliance on 3rd party tools.
- ▶ Lead the transition to a modern tech stack of React, TypeScript, and Apollo Client. Established development patterns, best practices, and guidelines for a development team numbering ~25 engineers.
- As an individual contributor, developed countless new features and prototypes for user testing, A/B experimentation, UX refinement, and bug fixes.

# **UX Prototype Developer**

HBO | UX Prototype Developer | 2016 - 2017

Developed high fidelity interactive prototypes for HBO's Digital Products team. Experimented with novel user experiences for multiple platforms including native TV apps, gaming consoles, and Amazon Echo. Refined interaction models for cursor focus/navigation and user search which are still utilized in HBO apps to this day.

# **UX** Designer

Tectonic Design Studio | UX Designer & Prototyping | 2014 – 2016

Applied design principles, processes, and user research to solve diverse solve client needs. Developed prototypes to articulate and validate hypotheses. Worked with Microsoft, Amazon, Bang & Olufsen, and more.